<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ethics | Pre-Released Ideas]]></title>
  <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/categories/ethics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-12T10:19:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://versionzero.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ben Burnett]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[yeah@right.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ethical Computing]]></title>
    <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2014/12/27/ethical-computing/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-27T22:21:02-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2014/12/27/ethical-computing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This essay is about performing and consuming computational cycles
ethically. Ethical computing is a means of computing with a focus on
reducing harmful externalities. We shall explore what an ethical
computation could look like from a variety of angles. We then argue
for a variety of means by which we might enable further development in
those areas.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Ethical Computation</h2>

<p>We shall explore each of the following topics in turn:</p>

<ol>
<li>The source of labor for the construction of physical computers</li>
<li>Sources of materials used in the construction of computer hardware</li>
<li>Sources of power used for the creation of computing cycles
(i.e. running the computer hardware)</li>
<li>Consumer, academic, industrial, and business influences on the
in-expense of computing products</li>
</ol>


<p>Later. we shall discus some possible solutions and , including:</p>

<ol>
<li>Frugal computing: the re-purposing of old computer hardware to
offset the costs associated with the disposal as well as powering
the hardware.</li>
</ol>


<p>We will focus on <em>popular</em> account of this issue, rather than a
densely inassesible accademic treatment. Not that we believe this will
lessen the power of the argument; we hope, instead, to make it more
readable and multimedia sourced. Using news articles and video sources
from TEDx, etc. we hope to broaden the audience and impact for this
topic. We believe this more important than the strict rigor of
academia&hellip; for the time being.</p>

<h2>Sources of Labor</h2>

<p>We begin with the human means of production. The party-line tells us
sweatshops are bad, immoral, unethical, torturous, etc.. The opposite
has been argued by
<a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/leslie_t_chang_the_voices_of_china_s_workers?language=en">Leslie T. Chang</a>:
According to Chang, the sweatshops can enable upward social,
economic. and educational movement&mdash;even if not in every instance. In
other words, the jobs create a more educated and highly skilled
workforce, and open up new possitions for further future workforce
accention. Clearly, this is not the whole picture: not all workers get
out, not all places are good or even comprehendible places to work;
however, that there exists exceptions is hopeful. It means there are
examples for new companies to sustain cheap labour, without
nessesarily being compromizingly opressive and exploitative&mdash;though
they still might be considered these things, by &ldquo;western&rdquo; standards.</p>

<p><em>In progress</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
