<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Me | Pre-Released Ideas]]></title>
  <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/categories/me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-12T10:19:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://versionzero.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ben Burnett]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[yeah@right.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Note About Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2013/02/16/a-note-about-me/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-16T18:20:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2013/02/16/a-note-about-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been using computers for as long as I can remember.</p>

<p>I broke and fixed my first computer at the age of 7, and I&rsquo;ve been
hooked ever since.  It has been a while since I concentrated strictly
on the internals of machines. I became fascinated with software
construction at age 10, after joining a school computer club. We
learnt how to use our trigonometry lessons to make something happen on
the screen. It was never fast nor pretty but it is was fun.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I have long stopped keeping up with the latest hardware
releases. Instead, I focus on the architecture I am currently
targeting. Despite not attending to the latest trends in consumer
hardware, I still keep myself informed about larger trends or shifts
in hardware design. I am currently particularly interested in multi­
and many-core systems: from how their cache and register memory is
arranged, what new concurrency primitives the cores support, all the
way to how they shepherd bits between cores and even other physical
CPUs.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been developing software professionally for almost 17 years
now. I&rsquo;ve written critical systems-level code; database applications;
elaborate, native and aesthetically pleasing graphical user
interfaces; highly parallel and distributed systems; as well as basic
utilities to help myself and others close to me perform everyday task
more pleasantly. Many of these projects have been developed using a
variety of languages and a diverse set of tools. The remaining ones
were written in C.</p>

<p>I prefer to use stable languages and mature tools for &ldquo;production&rdquo;
code. However, experimenting with new languages and novel tools for
small projects is something I continue to do often&ndash;for better or
worse. Ultimately though, I like writing: I like writing code, I like
writing about code, I like writing documentation for code, and I adore
writing tutorials on how to use code. The latter two tend to suffer
the most when I am busy, but only because it is usually the part that
requires the most care to get correct. As far as I can tell, there are
no automated tests for good explanations.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
