<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>versionzero</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://versionzero.org/feeds/poetry.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://versionzero.org/</id><updated>2018-01-14T02:14:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Harbouring Hate</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/blog/2018/01/14/harbouring-hate/index.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-14T02:14:00-07:00</published><author><name>Ben Burnett</name></author><id>tag:versionzero.org,2018-01-14:blog/2018/01/14/harbouring-hate/index.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cautiously and carefully he crept. It was critical he not be seen. His
mark, a car -- a carefully crafted and curated masterpiece of motored
magic -- sat waiting, longing for his touch. This is the part he
loved: the time before the grand exit, when anything seemed
possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further firing his excitement was a crowded celebration above. The
chatter of the crowd reached down the hills, through the trees, over
the grass, and meet his ears with titillation. The chatter was loud
and proud, but meaningless. Large groups congregated and
exaggerated. It was like watching group masterbation, but without any
nervous hesitation. They engaged their own vanity and let loose
stinging statement shaped to shear and decisively destroy other
egos. These are the people for whom he harboured hate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lock came easily -- the click of the bolt was orgasmic. Again he
crept, this time around the door and into the seat. It welcomed him
into its embrace, pulling him gracefully into place. He savoured the
moment. Perhaps he could keep it, he wondered... briefly. But the
reality of his humble and hopeless life hummed in is his head. This
was not to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He pushed a button and the engine came to life. It purred passionately
as the exhaust poured sensually over everything in its reach. He
reveled in the moment, paralyzed with pleasure. Then he snapped to,
depressed the clutch, shifted down, pressed the gas, and drove off
swiftly into the night. With no hesitation, quickly towards his final
destination.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Albera"></category><category term="Prairie"></category><category term="Crime"></category></entry><entry><title>Suddenly Saskatchewan</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/blog/2018/01/14/suddenly-saskatchewan/index.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-14T02:14:00-07:00</published><author><name>Ben Burnett</name></author><id>tag:versionzero.org,2018-01-14:blog/2018/01/14/suddenly-saskatchewan/index.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Suddenly Saskatchewan -- the land of the living skies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shock of the prairies was visceral and deep. He was half way from
home: half way from his new home and half way from his old one. He
wasn't far enough to miss his old one, but he was close enough to be
nervous of his new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He'd opted to leave everything behind. His things were packed into a
small cube in the fringes of an old industrial park. His friends in
their homes. His former life in a bag in the first available garbage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He carried on, not thinking to deeply about what would come along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was still in the prairies, but on the move. It was flatter than
Alberta, but still, it felt familiar. He came across a point of
interest. It - like most of the drive - was flat, too. Possibly the
point was that the flatness was of particular interest. He didn't know
-- there was no further information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He carried on, zig-zagging his way northeast, towards his destination,
leaving his former life behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike long drives in his youth, this one was draining. Both
physically and emotionally. He missed his friends and the benefits
that came with them. But not enough to go back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He carried on, in no hurry, through the wind and a slight worry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were many small towns along the way. One was a paradise away
from home, or at least that's what they said it was. Who knows what
they meant by that, it seemed barren and deserted. If quiet was
paradise, then it would have been the Caribbean. Minus the people, the
beaches, and the booze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon he would arrive at his destination and begin the task of making a
home. Though he was not sure what that would look like, the idea
appealed to him. This time he'd do it right. He'd get to know people
and step outside his zone of comfort. This excited him and made him
nervous at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He carried on, reflecting on his new home away from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He carried on, motoring through the discomfort of things left behind
and things to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He carried on, through the wind swept prairies that were his home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He carried on.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Saskatchewan"></category><category term="Prairie"></category></entry><entry><title>The Psychologist</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/blog/2018/01/14/the-psychologist/index.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-14T01:06:00-07:00</published><author><name>Ben Burnett</name></author><id>tag:versionzero.org,2018-01-14:blog/2018/01/14/the-psychologist/index.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looking over at Steve -- who was having his usual chatty morning,
standing by the window, soaking in the sun -- I wondered if he was
having a good conversation. Was it interesting? He seemed to laugh a
lot, so it must be good. Right? Looking back, I think I envied his
ability to talk to someone at any time. What I didn't envy was that
which allowed him to do so. I considered wandering over and saying hi,
but the politeness in me always stopped me. I'm not sure if I would
ever have had the right timing -- maybe no one would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with schizophrenic is you never know if you're
interrupting.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Mental Health"></category><category term="Short"></category></entry></feed>