<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>versionzero</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://versionzero.org/feeds/writing.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://versionzero.org/</id><updated>2016-08-04T05:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Drifting to Sleep</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/blog/2016/08/04/sleep/index.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-04T05:00:00-06:00</published><author><name>Ben Burnett</name></author><id>tag:versionzero.org,2016-08-04:blog/2016/08/04/sleep/index.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;He sat in the bath tub with a bag on his head and a hose at the
ready. His hand on the nozzle calmly cured the angst of his life,
leaving nothing but dread. &lt;em&gt;Will my family understand?&lt;/em&gt; he
wondered. &lt;em&gt;Probably not,&lt;/em&gt; he concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had been a miserable life for him, as far as misery goes. He'd
never had a good head on his shoulders, never got what others saw. He
was confined to the simple life, and told he should be content with
what he had. But he had nothing--and he knew it. &lt;em&gt;Nothing worth
anything&lt;/em&gt;, he thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actually, I do have something,&lt;/em&gt; he corrected himself. &lt;em&gt;I have plenty
of regret, that's what I have. And anger; that too,&lt;/em&gt; he mused. He was
right, in a way. Nothing had come easy to him; but somethings had
come, nevertheless. These thoughts were useless now though, not enough
reverse his pending actions. No miracle would save his soul, no soul
could save his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's done, it's decided, nothing can stop it now,&lt;/em&gt; echoed a voice
much like his own, but somehow distinct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hiss of the hose hummed in his head. &lt;em&gt;It'll all be over soon,&lt;/em&gt; it
said. Slowly from then, he slipped silently to sleep. Descending down
in to the deep.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Fiction"></category><category term="Short Stories"></category></entry><entry><title>Drive</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/blog/2016/05/16/drive/index.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-16T05:00:00-06:00</published><author><name>Ben Burnett</name></author><id>tag:versionzero.org,2016-05-16:blog/2016/05/16/drive/index.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;He found himself driving across the prairies&amp;mdash;the road stretching
as far as the eye could see, undulating as the small rises and dips
smoothly rocked the car. He had drifted off, for who knows how
long&amp;mdash;certainly not him. He was driving south and in the far
distance, after where the road disappeared, the mountains rose like
waves in a far off storm terrorizing the deep ocean, where no one
visited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mountains looked like the buildings of his downtown, but with
softer edges, where more snow gathered than could be expected of a
high-rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was glad to be away from the city; the noise of life there had
always buzzed in his head like an insect stuck in the vent of a car
heater. He has often wished it would die down, that he would get used
to it; but, instead, it continued unabated: pestering his every moment
awake&amp;mdash;and when he was unlucky, his sleep. He was glad to be
away, but the foreign sight of the mountains in the distance made him
uneasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of the mountains seemed at odds with the flat demeanor of the
ground beneath him; the sudden rise evoked a sense of vertigo equaled
by his downward high-rise view. The sight made him uncomfortable, yet
still, he drove on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A town crept slowly in to view; it too was as foreign as the mountain
ranges that dwarfed it further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lull of the road had made him tired. He pulled over at the nearest
gas station and purchased a coffee. After returning to the car he
continued on, unsure of what he would do next, except drive towards
the rocky pillars that lay ahead, beyond the end of the road.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Fiction"></category><category term="Short Stories"></category></entry><entry><title>In Time</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/blog/2016/04/15/in-time-2/index.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-15T05:00:00-06:00</published><author><name>Ben Burnett</name></author><id>tag:versionzero.org,2016-04-15:blog/2016/04/15/in-time-2/index.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The problem with time travel is that it takes time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes time to go back and kill Hitler. You have to plan these
things, it's not like you can just hop in the machine and go back and
kill Hitler. You have to know how you are going to do it. You have to
know when and where he is going to be. Those are, of course, a matter
of history, but still, it's not like you can just show up at Nuremberg
and be like, hey, I'm going to kill Hitler. No. It just not going to
happen that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the problem with time travel. It takes time. Time I don't have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought my time machine a while ago. I couldn't afford the best
model, but it's not the worst either. It was on sale at Walmart, and a
buddy helped me get it home. I'd had it in the dining room for a few
days, since I hadn't gotten around to getting a dining room table. But
after a few days of languishing in the space, I decided it would be
better to have it stashed in the spare room. God knows why I have a
spare room&amp;mdash;I'm single and I have few visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People used their time machines for all sorts of things. My neighbor
took his kids to the hight of the Roman empire to watch a match
between some gladiator and another. I don't remember the details. But
his son got lost. By lost, I mean he was taken and killed. His wife
was also raped. Not that his son was raped, but that in addition to
his son being killed, his wife was rapped. I don't think it was the
holiday they expected. But what can you expect from a place like that?
It's certainly not Disney Land. Not that Disney Land is Disney Land
anymore, it closed after time machines became available, since
everyone starting finding their magic elsewhere. Well, not everyone
found magic. My neighbor certainly didn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why did I buy a time machine if I didn't take trips like my
neighbor? I don't know. Why do we buy anything ridiculous? Maybe to
show off to the neighbors. Not that mine would be that impressed
anymore. Maybe we do it to fill a void. Maybe we do it to invest back
in to our economy. Maybe we just do it because we like cool shit that
lets us dream a little. Isn't that why people buy lottery tickets?
They can't seriously think they are going to win, can they? What it
does do for them is give them the right to imagine what they would do
if they won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I've mentioned lottery tickets, you're probably thinking:
well, why couldn't you just go back and buy a winning lottery ticket?
Well, you can't. OK, I guess you could go back and get the ticket with
the winning numbers, but you can't come back and expect it to win. You
could the fist time. And someone did. That's why you can't do it
anymore. The lottery people caught on. Not that there was much to
catch on to, I mean, it's a bloody time machine, who wouldn't have
thought to go back and get the winning ticket, it's an obvious thing
to do. But the lottery has changed. There is only ever one winner,
aside from the lottery people who rake it in, it's the person who
makes the first claim. And trust me, it's never going to be
you. People have armies of travelers poised to find the right
timing. They go get the ticket and try to arrive back so that they are
just in time to claim it. Problem is, is that because there are so
many people doing it, they all appear at the same place at the same
time. It's not pretty. Not pretty at all. I saw it once when I was a
kid, one second there was a man in line, just waiting to claim his
winnings, when suddenly, POP!, a woman appeared right in him. There
where three more pops in quick succession, and what remained looked
like a Medusa figure with multiple heads. It was sick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. I don't do any of those things with my time machine. The things I
do with mine are far less interesting. I use my time machine to do the
laundry. It works like this: I forget to do the laundry, as usual, but
rather than staying up all night waiting for the old machines, I just
hop in my machine, go back a few hours and put it on. By the time I'm
back, it's done. Takes no time at all.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Fiction"></category><category term="Short Stories"></category><category term="Science Fiction"></category></entry><entry><title>Living Alone</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/blog/2016/04/10/living-alone/index.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-10T07:00:00-06:00</published><author><name>Ben Burnett</name></author><id>tag:versionzero.org,2016-04-10:blog/2016/04/10/living-alone/index.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The world started without him. It continued well after, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was born in a small rural Alberta town, just south of nowhere and
north of nothing important. His life was full of disappointment,
heart-break, and loved ones lost. Yet still, he enjoyed the days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, he enjoyed the breeze the would swoop down from the
mountains in the West, curl around his house like a cat circling it's
rest. The wind would crep in to every nook and cranny in the place,
laying silt on every surface available for rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He enjoyed the creak of the old wood and the whistle that came from
the tin roof that had long since become loose from the constant gusts
across the prairies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On most nights, the sound soothed him off to sleep. But not this
evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had been awake since 6 am, just before the sun had broken. But even
in the lateness of evening, he could not find a nod. His mind was
wandering, fixating upon the things that had gone wrong in his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had not been a social man. He had picked the house and the land he
inhabited to escape the city he had once visited for 10 years in his
youth. But the move had not always worked the trick he had hoped. His
mind still returned there, not letting him escape the tendrils
that had wound around his past, urban life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He thought of the man for whom the department store's doors had caught
his coat as he, the stranger, had been exiting with gifts piled high
for his children. He recalled the urge to help, the sense that it
would be polite, and even kind, to reach out and pull the door open so
as to release the man's coat from it's clutches. He also recalled how
he had simply moved on, not fulfilling his imagined nicety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This moment in his past had become a fixture in his frequent visits to
the past. He had no good reason to think this made him a bad person,
one lacking in a certain type of character. Yet still, it came back,
over and over again&amp;mdash;revisiting his guilt upon him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things like this occupied his mind a lot, and usually for no particular
reason, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had had a good day that day. He had cleaned the kitchen for the 3rd
time that month, and scrubbed the bathroom to a shimmer for the 8th. He
liked the order, but lacked the discipline to leave good enough alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was they way for him, the visits to the past came at least once a
week, but this evening was, in particular, unsatisfactorily
unpleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He rose out of bed and made his way to the kitchen for a glass of
milk, hoping that it might help calm his mind. Over the course of the
short walk from the bed to the fringe, he quietly committed himself to
returning to the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He hoped that his time in the house, in the wind, with it's creeks,
and it's groans, dropped in the prairies, just east of the mountains,
would not return to him during a sleepless night in the city.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Fiction"></category><category term="Short Stories"></category></entry></feed>