<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>versionzero</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://versionzero.org/feeds/writing.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://versionzero.org/</id><updated>2016-04-10T07:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Living Alone</title><link href="http://versionzero.org/blog/2016/04/10/living-alone/index.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-10T07:00:00-06:00</published><author><name>Ben Burnett</name></author><id>tag:versionzero.org,2016-04-10:blog/2016/04/10/living-alone/index.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The world started without him. It continued well after, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was born in a small rural Alberta town, just south of nowhere and
north of nothing important. His life was full of disappointment,
heart-break, and loved ones lost. Yet still, he enjoyed the days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, he enjoyed the breeze the would swoop down from the
mountains in the West, curl around his house like a cat circling it's
rest. The wind would crep in to every nook and cranny in the place,
laying silt on every surface available for rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He enjoyed the creak of the old wood and the whistle that came from
the tin roof that had long since become loose from the constant gusts
across the prairies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On most nights, the sound soothed him off to sleep. But not this
evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had been awake since 6 am, just before the sun had broken. But even
in the lateness of evening, he could not find a nod. His mind was
wandering, fixating upon the things that had gone wrong in his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had not been a social man. He had picked the house and the land he
inhabited to escape the city he had once visited for 10 years in his
youth. But the move had not always worked the trick he had hoped. His
mind still returned there, not letting him escape the tendrils
that had wound around his past, urban life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He thought of the man for whom the department store's doors had caught
his coat as he, the stranger, had been exiting with gifts piled high
for his children. He recalled the urge to help, the sense that it
would be polite, and even kind, to reach out and pull the door open so
as to release the man's coat from it's clutches. He also recalled how
he had simply moved on, not fulfilling his imagined nicety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This moment in his past had become a fixture in his frequent visits to
the past. He had no good reason to think this made him a bad person,
one lacking in a certain type of character. Yet still, it came back,
over and over again&amp;mdash;revisiting his guilt upon him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things like this occupied his mind a lot, and usually for no particular
reason, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had had a good day that day. He had cleaned the kitchen for the 3rd
time that month, and scrubbed the bathroom to a shimmer for the 8th. He
liked the order, but lacked the discipline to leave good enough alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was they way for him, the visits to the past came at least once a
week, but this evening was, in particular, unsatisfactorily
unpleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He rose out of bed and made his way to the kitchen for a glass of
milk, hoping that it might help calm his mind. Over the course of the
short walk from the bed to the fringe, he quietly committed himself to
returning to the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He hoped that his time in the house, in the wind, with it's creeks,
and it's groans, dropped in the prairies, just east of the mountains,
would not return to him during a sleepless night in the city.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Fiction"></category><category term="Short Stories"></category></entry></feed>