<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Update | Pre-Released Ideas]]></title>
  <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/categories/update/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-11T23:05:31-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://versionzero.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ben Burnett]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[yeah@right.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, World!]]></title>
    <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2014/12/03/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-03T14:19:10-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2014/12/03/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the token &ldquo;Hello, World!&rdquo; post. I&rsquo;m desperate for content, apparently.
There&rsquo;s clearly nothing pre-released about this.</p>

<p>Anyway, the hope and purpose of the site is to publish in-process work so I
can get feedback from anyone kind enough to provide some.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The content of the site will vary wildly in terms levels of difficulty. I haven&rsquo;t
picked a single topic audience, which I&rsquo;m told is bad, but I think I&rsquo;ll make up for
it by covering a variety of interesting and worthwhile topics. To give you a feel
for the disparity: some articles will be about how to configure the Transmission
torrent software for secure downloads; on the other end of the spectrum, I&rsquo;ll be
writing about my own interesting in image quality metrics, optimization, programming,
building distributed systems, etc.</p>

<p>The best advice I can give a reader is this: only read what seems interesting
to you. Then, and I think more importantly, send me your thoughts on what I&rsquo;ve
written, even if you have nothing nice to say. Ok, well, maybe say one nice thing,
I do, after all, have feelings. But do be critical, all of this is meant to be
picked apart.</p>

<p>Wrapping it up: hope you enjoy some of what is contained herein; the whole point
is to try to reach other people.</p>

<p>Best,
-B</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
