<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Dos | Pre-Released Ideas]]></title>
  <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/categories/dos/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-11T23:06:20-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://versionzero.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ben Burnett]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[yeah@right.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows Environment Variable Tricks]]></title>
    <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2008/08/29/windows-environment-variable-trick/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-29T18:10:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2008/08/29/windows-environment-variable-trick</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Arrays</h3>

<p>Although not explicitly supported, it is possible to make, let&rsquo;s call
them pseudo-arrays, in the environment with no fancy string parsing or
anything sloppy like that. It involves some clever uses of call
command to evaluate and extract values from the pseudo-arrays and well
positioned % signs to demarcate which environment variables we want
evaluated and when.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Lets look at a quick example to see the basic mechanism. Assignment
would be done as follows:</p>

<p><div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-batch" data-lang="batch"><span class="k">set</span> <span class="nv">count</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="m">1</span>
<span class="k">set</span> <span class="nv">var%count%</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="m">42</span></code></pre></div></p>

<p>There are two method to extract the value, while at the command prompt
use the %var%count%% form to extract the value:</p>

<p><div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-batch" data-lang="batch"><span class="k">call</span> <span class="k">echo</span> <span class="nv">%var%</span>count%%</code></pre></div></p>

<p>On the other hand, while within a batch file use the %%var%count%%%
form to extract the value:</p>

<p>
call echo %%var%count%%%</p>

<p>Note the extra strafing % signs. Both of the above expressions will
display the number 42, as expected; or maybe it&rsquo;s is surprising, it
all depends on your expectations and what you might consider
interesting and cool. Sadly, I do consider this cool; insofar as it
works on a straight out of the box Windows installation.  The
technique may look a little hairy, but it&rsquo;s quite useful. The above
will print the contents of var1 (i.e. 42) as we explained. We could
also replace the echo command with a set if we wanted to set some
other variable to the value in var1. Meaning the following is a valid
assignment at the command line:</p>

<p><div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-batch" data-lang="batch"><span class="k">call</span> <span class="k">set</span> <span class="nv">x</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nv">%var%</span>count%%</code></pre></div></p>

<p>Where:</p>

<p><div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-batch" data-lang="batch"><span class="k">echo</span> <span class="nv">%x%</span></code></pre></div></p>

<p>Would print the number 42, as we would expect. We can even carry out
arithmetic operations on these pseudo-arrays&#8217; values. For instance,
the following would subtract 2 from the value of varN:</p>

<p><div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-batch" data-lang="batch"><span class="k">call</span> <span class="k">set</span> <span class="n">/a</span> x<span class="o">=</span><span class="nv">%var%</span>N%%<span class="m">-2</span> <span class="p">&gt;</span><span class="n">nul</span></code></pre></div></p>

<p>Note that here we need to redirect the output to the nul port,
otherwise the result arithmetic operation would be printed to the
screen. Either way, this technique means that some rather advanced
operations can be done over a range of values, with little effort.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing Windows 95 Using Virtual PC]]></title>
    <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2007/12/13/windows-95-using-virtual-pc/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-13T04:34:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2007/12/13/windows-95-using-virtual-pc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Requirements</h3>

<ul>
<li>Windows 95 CD-ROM or disk image</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bootdisk.com/bootdisk.htm">Boot disk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.chrysocome.net/rawwrite">RawWrite</a></li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<h3>Installation</h3>

<ul>
<li>Create an ISO of your original <a
href="http://ben.versionzero.org/wiki/Burning_Disk_Images_%28i.e._ISO%2C_IMG%2C_etc.%29#In_Windows_95_.2F_98_.2F_ME_.2F_2000_.2F_XP_.2F_Server_2003_.2F_Vista"
class="external text" rel="nofollow">Windows 95 CD</a> or get a copy
from some someplace&hellip; Do this because otherwise it takes ages to
install; it&rsquo;s lightning fast with disk images as compared to real CD
media.</li>
<li>Create boot disks by using the Windows 95 Original (boot95a.exe)
program and writing it to a real floppy drive.  Then, using RawWrite
create the the disk image (call it, say boot95a.img).  In the end, I
only needed to use boot95a.img to get the whole thing to boot (so
don&rsquo;t even bother getting the Windows 95 Version B disk, unless you
absolutely cannot book with the first one).</li>
<li>Create a new Virtual Machine in Virtual PC with 64MB of RAM and 2GB
of disk space (the largest it can handle, I think). (I was
installing a game and I wanted to make sure there would be plenty of
room to spare.)</li>
<li>Start the new Virtual Machine and have Virtual PC capture both the
Win95.iso and boot95a.img disk, as a CD-ROM and floppy drive,
respectively.</li>
<li>Once the new Virtual Machine has started, used <code>FDISK</code> to
initialize the drive, then <code>FORMAT C: /S</code> to get it ready
for the OS. After the format is complete, which will be quick, copy
the following files from the floppy disk to the C: drive:</li>
</ul>


<p><div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-batch" data-lang="batch">copy config.sys C:\
copy autoexec.bat C:\
copy MSCDEX.EXE C:\
copy cd<span class="m">1</span>.sys C:\</code></pre></div></p>

<p>This ensures that you will actually have a CD-ROM drive during the
setup process.  How very convenient, don&rsquo;t you think?. You can even
copy-n&#8217;-paste the commands from here (that&rsquo;s why I wrote them that
way, so I can do it in the future), if you are lazy like me.  Then you
can have Virtual PC type it all in for you by selecting the Edit &gt;
Paste menu item (or if you’re a keyboard junky, then it&rsquo;s <b>Right
Alt + V</b> (yeah, not only it is the <i>Alt</i> key, instead of the
Ctrl key, but it&rsquo;s <i>only</i> the right Alt one, since the left one
is used as your escape route from the VM).  And don&rsquo;t worry, Windows
will actually get rid of your autoexec.bat after the installation is
complete, so you don&rsquo;t have to the leg work yourself.</p>

<ul>
<li>Now on to the fun part: Installing Window 95. (It’s called SETUP and it is located on the root of the CD-ROM, which should be the R: drive, if you used the same boot disks I did.)</li>
<li>When prompted for the CD key, if you have it saved in a file, just copy it out of there (remove the &lsquo;-&rsquo; and &lsquo;OEM&rsquo;, if it has it) and use Virtual PC to paste it into the Virtual Machine (fake the key strokes rock!). It&rsquo;s all about being lazy. Conceivably, one could write out all the required key strokes for an install, and simply paste them in to Virtual PC, to automate the installation; but, well, that&rsquo;s just silly, since there are much simpler ways of doing unattended installs.</li>
<li>When asked about hardware, if you are given a list, don&rsquo;t select any for now, we do that later, once the installation is complete. (There is are drivers on the <i>Virtual Machine Additions</i> ISO provided by Virtual PC.)</li>
<li>[Optional] During setup it asks to make a start-up disk, if you release boot95a.img and make a copy of it (re-name it to startup95.img, or something similar), you can capture the new disk image, and have the Windows 95 setup create a new start-up disk for you. Very exciting.</li>
<li>Once the installation is complete, release the floppy disk, because the seek noise on boot will drive you up the wall.  While you’re at it, you can also release the install media, since you won&rsquo;t need it anymore.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Networking</h3>

<p>Because of the way we installed Windows 95, the networking may not be
configured correctly.  To fix this open the <b>Control Panel</b> and
double click on the <b>Network</b> icon.  Once there, add click on
<b>Add&hellip;</b> and double click on <b>Protocol</b> in the component
list.  From the <b>Manufacturers</b> list, select <b>Microsoft</b> and
them, from the <b>Network Protocols</b> double click on <b>TCP/IP</b>.
Finally, click <b>OK</b> and allow Windows to go about it&rsquo;s rebooting
way.  Reboots always seem to make Windows happy.  If your computer is
ever frustrated, just reboot it, it&rsquo;ll make it smile.</p>

<h3>Service Pack</h3>

<p>Once you have the networking configured properly, it&rsquo;s time to update
Windows (as all good Windows users do, right?).  I found, to my
surprise, that the Windows 95 Service Pack was still available from
the Microsoft web-site.  Man, I&rsquo;d hate to be the person doing the
support for that.</p>

<p>You can get SP1 from
<a href="http://support.microsoft.com/kb/142794">here</a>. Be warned, however,
that using the old Internet Explorer with all these new fangled
JavaScript thingamabobs can be a little trying, to say the least.</p>

<h3>Notes</h3>

<p>Now, when you tell Virtual PC to <i>Install or Update Virtual Machine
Additions</i>, in the words of the venerable comedian Douglas Addams,
&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t Panic!&rdquo;, because it will just give you a weird error (the
kernel is missing a handy function to tell Virtual PC if a debugger is
running, if that means anything to you, great! If not, don&rsquo;t worry
about, it&rsquo;s not important anyway).  But this error really isn&rsquo;t an
error; you can ignore it and simple <i>Explore</i> the CD for the
setup program&hellip; Sadly, it turns out only the DOS applications
actually work on a Window 95 base install (and they do not play well
with Windows, so you have to exit to the command line and run
FSHARE.EXE to get <b>Folder Sharing</b> to work&mdash; and even then,
it&rsquo;s only in DOS that you can access that drive.  If you try to run
Windows once it has been loaded, Windows goes all wonky&mdash; try it,
if you don&rsquo;t believe me) What really strikes me about this, is that
even the OS/2 additions work&mdash;and who even uses that OS anymore?!
(says the man installing Windows 95)&mdash;so why doesn&rsquo;t it work on a
stock Windows 95 install?  Maybe some hints can be gathered from
<a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/virtual_pc_guy/archive/2007/10/30/installing-dos-additions-under-vpc-2007.aspx">here</a></p>

<h3>Some Software Updates</h3>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internet Explorer 5.0]]></title>
    <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2007/12/13/internet-explorer-5.0/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-13T04:34:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2007/12/13/internet-explorer-5.0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the final release version of IE5 released on March
18th. Although this version has some new features as well as some
enhancements to some old ones, it is certainly one of the better
browsers in the world so far. You may want to keep in mind that this
program can cause noticeable speed decreases in system performance
after installation. Gladly, you can uninstall this software and be
left with any previous versions in tact the way you may have left
them. (Unfortunately, the only copies I could find are Cintek branded
ones.)</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Internet Explorer 5.0 for 32-bit Windows Operating Systems</h3>

<ul>
<li>Minimum Requirements: 486DX/66MHz or higher, Windows 95/98, 12MB RAM,
56MB disk space.</li>
<li>Download Size: 37MB</li>
</ul>


<h3>Internet Explorer 5.0 for 16-bit Windows Operating Systems</h3>

<ul>
<li>Minimum Requirements: 486DX or higher, Windows 3.1 or NT 3.5, 12MB
RAM for browser only installation (16MB RAM if using the Java
VM). 30MB disk space to run setup.</li>
<li>Download Size: 9.4MB</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing Windows NT 4.0 Workstation Using Virtual PC]]></title>
    <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2007/09/23/windows-nt-4.0-workstation-using-virtual-pc/"/>
    <updated>2007-09-23T04:34:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2007/09/23/windows-nt-4.0-workstation-using-virtual-pc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Introduction</h3>

<p>I assume a lot about you&rsquo;re background in these tutorials. They are
primarily for myself, because I have a tendency to forget things more
often than not, so don&rsquo;t be too distressed and come calling on me if I
don&rsquo;t hold your hand through the whole thing. (Sorry, it&rsquo;s 12:04am,
and it&rsquo;s been a long day.)</p>

<h3>Requirements</h3>

<ul>
<li>Windows NT Workstation CD-ROM or disk image</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<h3>Installation</h3>

<ul>
<li>Create an ISO of your original <a
href="http://ben.versionzero.org/wiki/Burning_Disk_Images_%28i.e._ISO%2C_IMG%2C_etc.%29#In_Windows_95_.2F_98_.2F_ME_.2F_2000_.2F_XP_.2F_Server_2003_.2F_Vista"
class="external text" rel="nofollow">Windows 95 CD</a> or get a copy
from some someplace&hellip; Do this because otherwise it takes ages to
install; it&rsquo;s lightning fast with disk images as compared to real CD
media.</li>
<li>Create a new Virtual Machine in Virtual PC with 64MB of RAM and 4GB
of disk space, or change all that to your requirements.</li>
<li>Start the new Virtual Machine and have Virtual PC capture the
WinNT.iso (or whatever you called it) as a CD-ROM.</li>
<li>Once the new Virtual Machine has started, use your common since and
format the drive using NTFS. After the format is complete, which
will be quick, you can sit back and let the setup do its thing.</li>
<li>On the first boot, it will look like nothing is
happening&hellip; <i>forever</i>. But it is actually doing something, so
just be patient.  Even though you selected NTFS as your file system,
it first must be formatted as FAT and then converted.  I&rsquo;m sure
there is some weird historical reason for this, but I don&rsquo;t know it
of hand.  My best guess is that they had a very quick and easy way
to format a FAT partition (so the actual install phase was fast),
put some run once utilities on it, and then you boot for the first
time, it blows the whole FAT partition away and puts an NTFS one in
its place.</li>
<li>When prompted for the CD key, if you have it saved in a file, just
copy it out of there (remove the &lsquo;-&rsquo; and &lsquo;OEM&rsquo;, if it has it) and
use Virtual PC to paste it into the Virtual Machine (fake the key
strokes rock!). It&rsquo;s all about being lazy. Unfortunately, unlike
other OS installers, the NT one is not smart enough to skip from one
edit control to the next, once the edit control is full.  This means
that instead of being able to just paste the whole thing, like you
can for Windows 95, you must paste each part individually, and then
TAB to the next edit control manually.  It&rsquo;s a small irritation, but
if you have you speakers turned up, you&rsquo;ll know you entered too many
characters in on field, because Windows will beep repeatedly at
you. (My ears leant that the hard way.)</li>
<li>When asked about networking, just say you are on a <b>Wired to the
network</b> and let NT detect the network adapter for you, by
clicking on the search button.  The <b>TCP/IP Protocol</b> is
enabled by default.  For most people this is sufficient, but you can
also select <b>NetBEUI</b> for novelty&rsquo;s sake.</li>
<li>The next step allows you to install new services, I added <b>Simple
TCP/IP Services</b> and more importantly&mdash;for my network,
anyway&mdash;<b>Microsoft TCP/IP Printing</b>.</li>
<li>(<em>Optional</em>) During setup it asks to make a start-up disk, if you
copy <code>D:\SUPPORT\HQTOOL\NTHQ</code> and re-name it to
startupNT.img, or something similar, you can capture the new disk
image, and have the Windows NT setup create a new start-up disk for
you. How ever so clever.</li>
<li>Once the installation is complete, release the floppy disk, because
otherwise you&rsquo;ll find yourself in recovery land.  Also, I suggest
disabling the auto detection of the floppy disk, as the seek noise
on boot will drive you up the wall. (Maybe not the first time, but
it will eventually get to you, I promise.) While you’re at it, you
can also release the install media, since you won&rsquo;t need it anymore.</li>
<li>It actually turns out that it&rsquo;s just boots in general that take
forever, just be patient.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Networking</h3>

<p>Because of the way we installed Windows 95, the networking may not be
configured correctly.  To fix this open the <b>Control Panel</b> and
double click on the <b>Network</b> icon.  Once there, add click on
<b>Add&hellip;</b> and double click on <b>Protocol</b> in the component
list.  From the <b>Manufacturers</b> list, select <b>Microsoft</b> and
them, from the <b>Network Protocols</b> double click on <b>TCP/IP</b>.
Finally, click <b>OK</b> and allow Windows to go about it&rsquo;s rebooting
way.  Reboots always seem to make Windows happy.  If your computer is
ever frustrated, just reboot it, it&rsquo;ll make it smile.</p>

<h3>Service Pack</h3>

<p>Once you have the networking configured properly, it&rsquo;s time to update
Windows (as all good Windows users do, right?).  I found, to my
surprise, that the Windows 95 Service Pack was still available from
the Microsoft web-site.  Man, I&rsquo;d hate to be the person doing the
support for that.</p>

<p>You can get SP6a from
<a href="http://support.microsoft.com/kb/152734">here</a>. Be warned, however,
that you will have to do this on your host machine and transfer the
files over the network, as the version of IE that ships with NT (on my
old version, anyway— packing a full SP1, oh yeah!) won&rsquo;t even open
www.google.com.</p>

<h3>Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.cintek.com/download/ie5.htm">Internet Explorer 5.0</a></li>
<li><a href="http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/netframework/aa569264.aspx">Microsoft .NET Framework 1.1 Redistributable</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Now, when you tell Virtual PC to Install or Update Virtual Machine
Additions, in the words of the venerable comedian Douglas Addams,
&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t Panic!&rdquo;, because it will just give you a weird error (the
kernel is missing a handy function to tell Virtual PC if a debugger is
running, if that means anything to you, great! If not, don&rsquo;t worry
about, it&rsquo;s not important anyway). But this error really isn&rsquo;t an
error; you can ignore it and simple Explore the CD for the setup
program&hellip; Sadly, it turns out only the DOS applications actually work
on a Window 95 base install (and they do not play well with Windows,
so you have to exit to the command line and run FSHARE.EXE to get
Folder Sharing to work— and even then, it&rsquo;s only in DOS that you can
access that drive. If you try to run Windows once it has been loaded,
Windows goes all wonky— try it, if you don&rsquo;t believe me.) What really
strikes me about this is that even the OS/2 additions work—and who
even uses that OS anymore?! (Says the man installing Windows 95)—so
why doesn&rsquo;t it work on a stock Windows 95 install?</p>

<h3>Some Software Updates</h3>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doskey Macros]]></title>
    <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2002/08/20/doskey-macros/"/>
    <updated>2002-08-20T20:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2002/08/20/doskey-macros</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Doskey macros are a wonderful thing, even today with the GUI goodness
Windows offers, there is still many a reason to drop down to the
command line. Now, most Linux and UNIX folks will laugh at the
arguably abysmal tool set given by the good old DOS prompt, but it can
be made just a little more interesting if you start using doskey in
conjunction with a set of batch files.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Below is a very simple template doskey macro/batch file which will
first execute as a batch file, and then use itself as a doskey macro
file. Hopefully it will get you started down a more efficient command
line route. Or you might just find it a clever, but useless mess.</p>

<p><div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-batch" data-lang="batch">;<span class="o">=</span> @<span class="k">echo</span> <span class="k">off</span>
;<span class="o">=</span> rem <span class="k">Call</span> DOSKEY and use this file as the macrofile
;<span class="o">=</span> <span class="nv">%SystemRoot%</span>\system<span class="m">32</span>\doskey <span class="n">/listsize=1000</span> <span class="n">/macrofile=%0%</span>
;<span class="o">=</span> rem In batch mode<span class="p">,</span> jump to the end of the file
;<span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">goto</span> <span class="nl">end</span>
;<span class="o">=</span> rem <span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;
;<span class="o">=</span> rem *   Filename: aliases.bat
;<span class="o">=</span> rem *    Version: <span class="m">1</span>.<span class="m">0</span>
;<span class="o">=</span> rem *     Author: Ben Burnett <span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">a</span> href<span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#x74;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;&amp;#x6d;&amp;#x65;&amp;#64;&amp;#x63;&amp;#115;&amp;#46;&amp;#119;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#x63;&amp;#x2e;&amp;#101;&amp;#x64;&amp;#117;&quot;</span>&gt;&amp;#x<span class="m">6</span>d;&amp;#x<span class="m">65</span>;&amp;#x<span class="m">40</span>;&amp;#x<span class="m">63</span>;&amp;#<span class="m">115</span>;&amp;#<span class="m">46</span>;&amp;#<span class="m">119</span>;&amp;#x<span class="m">69</span>;&amp;#<span class="m">115</span>;&amp;#x<span class="m">63</span>;&amp;#x<span class="m">2</span>e;&amp;#<span class="m">101</span>;&amp;#<span class="m">100</span>;&amp;#<span class="m">117</span>;&lt;<span class="n">/a&gt;</span>
;<span class="o">=</span> rem *    Purpose: Simple<span class="p">,</span> but useful aliases; this can be done by
;<span class="o">=</span> rem *             other means&amp;ndash;of course&amp;ndash;but this is dead simple and
;<span class="o">=</span> rem *             works <span class="k">on</span> EVERY Windows machine <span class="k">on</span> the planet.
;<span class="o">=</span> rem *    History:
;<span class="o">=</span> rem * <span class="m">22</span><span class="n">/01/2002:</span> File Created (Syncrude Canada).
;<span class="o">=</span> rem * <span class="m">01</span><span class="n">/05/2007:</span> Updated author&amp;rsquo;s address<span class="p">,</span> added new macros<span class="p">,</span> a
;<span class="o">=</span> rem *             history and some new helpful comments.
;<span class="o">=</span> rem * <span class="m">19</span><span class="n">/06/2007:</span> Added Notepad<span class="p">,</span> Explorer and Emacs macros.
;<span class="o">=</span> rem * <span class="m">20</span><span class="n">/06/2007:</span> Fixed doskey macrofile<span class="o">=</span> path problem: it is now not
;<span class="o">=</span> rem *             a relative path<span class="p">,</span> so it can be called from anywhere.
;<span class="o">=</span> rem &lt;<span class="n">/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</span>

<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">p</span>&gt;;<span class="o">=</span> Doskey aliases
h<span class="o">=</span>doskey <span class="n">/history&lt;/p&gt;</span>

<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">p</span>&gt;;<span class="o">=</span> File listing enhancements
ls<span class="o">=</span>dir <span class="n">/x</span> $<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">em</span><span class="p">&gt;</span>
<span class="n">l</span><span class="o">=</span>dir <span class="n">/x</span> $&lt;<span class="n">/em&gt;</span>
ll<span class="o">=</span>dir <span class="n">/w</span> $<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">em</span><span class="p">&gt;</span>
<span class="n">la</span><span class="o">=</span>dir <span class="n">/x</span> <span class="n">/a</span> $&lt;<span class="n">/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</span>

<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">p</span>&gt;;<span class="o">=</span> Directory navigation
up<span class="o">=</span><span class="k">cd</span> ..
pd<span class="o">=</span>pushd&lt;<span class="n">/p&gt;</span>

<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">p</span>&gt;;<span class="o">=</span> Copy and move macros
cp<span class="o">=</span>copy
mv<span class="o">=</span>move&lt;<span class="n">/p&gt;</span>

<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">p</span>&gt;;<span class="o">=</span> Delete macros
rm<span class="o">=</span><span class="k">del</span> <span class="n">/p</span> $<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">em</span><span class="p">&gt;</span>
<span class="n">rmf</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="k">del</span> <span class="n">/q</span> $&lt;<span class="n">/em&gt;</span>
rmtmp<span class="o">=</span><span class="k">del</span> <span class="n">/q</span> <span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">em</span>&gt;~ &lt;<span class="n">/em&gt;#</span> <span class="m">2</span><span class="p">&gt;</span><span class="n">nul</span>&lt;<span class="n">/p&gt;</span>

<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">p</span>&gt;;<span class="o">=</span> Fast access to Notepad
n<span class="o">=</span>notepad $*&lt;<span class="n">/p&gt;</span>

<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">p</span>&gt;;<span class="o">=</span> Fast access to Explorer
c<span class="o">=</span>explorer .&lt;<span class="n">/p&gt;</span>

<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">p</span>&gt;;<span class="o">=</span> <span class="nl">:end</span>
;<span class="o">=</span> rem <span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">strong</span>&gt;
;<span class="o">=</span> rem * EOF - Don&amp;rsquo;t remove the following line.  It clears out the &amp;lsquo;;&amp;rsquo;
;<span class="o">=</span> rem * macro. Were using it because there is no support <span class="k">for</span> comments
;<span class="o">=</span> rem * in a DOSKEY macro file.
;<span class="o">=</span> rem &lt;<span class="n">/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;</span>
;<span class="o">=</span></code></pre></div></p>

<p>It abuses the fact that the command prompt in Windows will silently
eat the &lsquo;;=&rsquo; prefix, while doskey will treat it as a macro being
re-defined over and over again.</p>

<p>EDIT: Honourable mention on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4186427/how-do-you-write-comments-in-doskey-macro-files">StackOverflow</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
