<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Git | Pre-Released Ideas]]></title>
  <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/categories/git/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-21T17:22:04-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://versionzero.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ben Burnett]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[yeah@right.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revision Control Is Not Just a Backup Tool]]></title>
    <link href="http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/revision-control-is-not-a-backup-tool/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T13:04:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://versionzero.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/revision-control-is-not-a-backup-tool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I made the mistake, when I started using revision control&mdash;like many
others might have done&mdash;to think of it, conceptually, as a backup
mechanism. This, it turns out, I believe, is naive, and a very poor
characterization of the power of revision control. Let me explain.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>First things first: starting an opinion piece by contradicting
yourself is a gamble, but I hope you&rsquo;ll still hear me out.  And notice
I do call this an opinion: I&rsquo;ve run across to many blog posts that
make bold statements of fact, but provide little more than anecdotal
evidence to support their claim.  There very well may be evidence for
what I am about to say, but I have not done any background work on the
topic. (I will amend this article as my understanding of the tools
improves.)</p>

<p>So what&rsquo;s the contradiction? Well, revision control tools actualy are
backup tools: i.e. they obviously provide a way to recover old data.
Moreover, there are backup and synchronization tools that use revision
control under the hood.  But these uses only encompass a small subset
of the power of revision control.  In what follows, we shall endeavour
to present some of the important distinctions between revision control
and backup tools.</p>

<h2>What is Revision Control?</h2>

<p>We have all invented or borrowed a (possibly naive) system for
revisions to electronic documents.  In some cases, these revisions can
be seen as dated copies of a file:</p>

<ul>
<li>CV-2010-09-12.doc;</li>
<li>CV-2012-04-09.doc;</li>
<li>etc.</li>
</ul>


<p>The intent, presumably, is to keep a history of the changes in the
content as well as preserving any content removed in subsequent
revisions.  This type of revision is practical for a small number of
documents with fairly stable content: a curriculum vitae may change
infrequently enough that there may only ever be a few revisions.
Source code is another story.</p>

<p>Source code revisions are useful for the same reasons CV revisions
are.  Revisions for code are even more useful when there are
(possibly) many people working over a long period of time on a
project.  We will imagine this time period to be 20 years.  This
length of time can almost ensure that there will exist code that was
originally written by one person and subsequently updated by
others. This is where revisions come in to play.</p>

<p>Comments are one thing, they tell the reader what the code is supposed
to do and why it was decided that it should be done that way&ndash;for
better or worse.  Comments are discussions about code in a highly
localized environment.  Documentation can be used to provide the
more general purpose of the program, but there is still information
missing.  A revision control system allows changes in code to be
tracked but also explained in a different forum than would be
appropriate for comments.  It&rsquo;s easy to imagine a body of code that is
20 years old will have files and sub-systems that have changes a dozen
or so times.  Keeping a record of all the comments from previous code
that is no longer relevant to current code is a bad idea&ndash;it can
confuse the intent of the code.  Instead, the changes can be cataloged
as part of a revision; that is, they will still describe the code
present in the old versions, but do not need to be preserved in new
versions.  Furthermore, the revision comments can include a discussion
on the nature of the changes.  In many cases this information is
interesting and worth preserving, but is generally not useful to have
at the code or documentation level: the fidelity of the content is too
distinct from those.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
